A Guide to the Marcus L. Oliver Correspondence, 1947-2010 (Bulk 1950-1985)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Marcus L. Oliver Correspondence, 1947-2010 (Bulk 1950-1985)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2009-096
1.4 Cubic Feet 1 box
The collection contains business correspondence from Oliver's tenure with the Virginia Tech Alumni Association (1950-1968) and the University of the South Alumni Association. The collection also includes personal correspondence from 1947 to 2010.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the Marcus L. Oliver Correspondence was donated to Special Collections in June 2009, though some materials pre-date this (there is at least one donation from 2004). Additional materials were donated in 2010.
Biographical Information
Marcus L. Oliver graduated from VPI in 1947 with a BS in Argicultural Education. In 1949, he obtained a MS from the University of North Carolina. From 1949 to 1968, he worked for the Virginia Tech Alumni Association in several capacities: Assistant Secretary (1949-1960), Secretary (1960-1965), Director of Alumni Affairs (1965-1966), and Director of Placement (1966-1968). After Virginia Tech, Oliver served as the Director of Development, then Director of Annual Giving at the University of the South in Sewanee, Tennessee.
Scope and Content
The collection contains business correspondence from Oliver's tenure with the Virginia Tech Alumni Association (1950-1968) and the University of the South Alumni Association. The collection also includes personal correspondence from 1947 to 2010. Letters in the collection are written to Oliver by numerous correspondents. Other materials include carbon or onion skin copies of letters by Oliver, created in the course of professional and personal activities. In some cases, correspondence to and from the same person is clipped or stapled together.
Correspondents significant to the history of Virginia Tech, as well as those with large contributions to the collection are listed under the "Index Terms" section of the finding aid below. Major topics include Virginia Tech Alumni Association business, Virginia Tech German Club events, and general professional correspondence. The collection also contains photocopies of a small number of articles by Oliver for The Techgram in 1950.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically. Correspondence is in folders according to the first letter of the last name. Each letter of the alphabet has one to two folders. Although multiple pieces of correspondence by the same author are sometimes stapled or paper-clipped together, please note this is not always the case. The original order of the materials has been maintained.
Additional materials processed in July 2017 were added to the back of the appropriate alphabetical folder.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Alumni Association Records, 1905–present, RG29.
Board of Visitors Records, C. Eugene Rowe Records, Ms89-005.
G. Preston Frazer Collection, Ms2009-098. Finding aid available on the Virginia Heritage database.
Office of the President Records, Thomas M. Hahn Records, 1962-1974, RG 2/11. Inventory available on the University Archives webpage.
Index Terms
Persons:
Cahill, Edward; Cochran, Edward; Dean, James W., 1920-; Dixon, James; Fabian, G. Craig; Forbes, Charles M.; Frazer, George Preston; Gordon, Charles O.; Godsey, John D.; Gustin, Harry; Hahn, T. Marshall, Jr. (Thomas Marshall), 1926-2016; Horton, Miles C., Jr.; Johnson, Adger S.; Johnston, G. Burke (George Burke), 1907-1995; King, Helen G.; Marmion, William H. (William Henry), 1907-; Mayo, Elizabeth; Mayo, Fitzhugh; Musser, Harry P.; Oliver, John; Oliver, Marcus L.; Norcross, William Ernest; Roberts, James; Rowe, C. Eugene; Powell, James V.; Roberts, Anne; Tatum, Omar; Taylor, Gregory C.; Shackelford, George Green, 1921-2010; Shackelford, Grace; Vernon, William D.; Wasko, Barbara; Webb, Jack
Corporate Names:
German Club. Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Alumni Foundation
Family Names:
Oliver family
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute. Alumni Association; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Correspondence, A, 1951-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, B (2 folders), 1962-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, C (2 folders), 1953-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, D, 1952-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, E, 1957-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, F (2 folders), 1953-2010 (Box 1, Folder 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, G (2 folders), 1949-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, H (2 folders), 1964-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, I-J (2 folders), 1949-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, K (2 folders), 1950-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, L, 1953-2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, M-N (2 folders), 1949-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, O, 1948-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, P, 1950-1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Q-R (2 folders), 1948-1997 (Box 1, Folder 23, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, S (2 folders), 1950-2010 (Box 1, Folder 25, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, T (2 folders), 1950-2010 (Box 1, Folder 27, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, U-V, 1950-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, W-Z (2 folders), 1960-2002 (Box 1, Folder 30, Folder 31)
- The Techgram, Alumni Association articles by Oliver, 2017-07-15 (Box 1, Folder 32)